So now I've completed my scoring on the top ring and the bottom ring.
The next thing I'm going to do is take a paint brush, you could do this with your finger or sponge, and simply go all the way around and put slip all over my scored area, like this.
I'm going to repeat the same process here, working my way all the way around giving lots of slip on there, like that.
Okay, so now I've completed slipping my pot and as you can see I have a nice thick layer on the top and the bottom.
When doing a two part vase like this you might want to then turn the wheel and simply make some circular marks to let you know where to put it on.
We can get rid of these afterwards, these marks.
So now we have an idea of where we want to stick the top.
Now we're going to take this top, turn it over, simply place it on to one of our rings, like so, maybe turn the wheel see how centered it is.
You could repeat the centering process with a needle tool to get this absolutely and correctly in place, however that looks pretty good.
So now what I'm going to want to do, they make a variety of tools to go inside.
I like to just simply use a wet a wooden spoon like this, wet it down and put it on the inside.
And I'm going to use this as a support to push down the top part onto the bottom part.
I'm going to stick my spoon inside and then move the wheel around and apply quite a lot of force onto the base there.
So that the two parts become one.
Again, holding this on the underside there, you can see that edge is being used, and pushing it up underneath, and pushing my finger down on the top to ensure a nice connection.
I'm actually applying more pressure than what it may look like.
Straight down you can actually see the clay working down into the body of the other part.
Okay so now I've pushed the top part down onto the bottom part, the slip is there, I might want to take some extra slip afterwards and just simply go around the edge there.
Then I can go over and take out any grooves that I might have put into the clay, like so.
Perhaps take a sponge just to wipe everything down at the end, like that.
Any slur that might have gotten on there, take it off.
Okay, so as you can see we have now completed the throwing and assembly of our two part vase.
In the next section I will just be talking briefly about tips on finishing this up, and getting it ready for the kiln.
And we'll be talking about that next.